Snebu Samuel

▲ Personal Information



Address: Dubai, United Arab Emirates **Phone number:** 00-971-566713006

Email address: snebusamuel@yahoo.com

Profile

An accomplished IT Professional with more than 12 years of experience working in Companies, Institutes & Hospitality Industry. With a solid background in Information Technology particularly in Administration, Management, Networking, Training & Organizational Development, Software, Hardware & Network Trouble Shooting and top-notch abilities in organizing workflows, solving complex problems and making accurate decisions based on sound judgment and analytical strengths. Experienced with leading teams driving projects. Seek to bring knowledge and abilities to a new position with a growing team. Also with a background in Hospitality & Pharmacy Industry. Highly motivated and experienced, with a positive and confident outlook, enjoy overcoming obstacles which require discipline, enthusiasm and no small measure of mental or physical aptitude, to meet deadlines and aim to contribute and to make a difference to everything I do.

Work experience

09/2019 – present Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Information Technology Manager Crowne Plaza® Hotels & Resorts

Championing hotel pre-opening phase, snagging, & projects pertaining to IT infrastructure & system; and ensure timely completion of the projects. In charge of the IT strategy – lead the development and implementation of hotel IT strategy while complying with IHG corporate IT governance. Identify and evaluate innovative, but fit for purpose technologies supporting business operations to meet its current and future guests' and operational requirements reflecting the rapid changes in guests' behavior. Set IT objectives, managing performance, developing staff and providing formal and informal feedback in order to maximize overall performance and IT team motivation. Strategically plan and operationally execute annual budget for the department as well as identify, plan and manage various IT hardware and software projects in all project stages to ensure project objectives are accomplished within time. Protect the confidentiality, integrity and availability of the company's data and IT infrastructure. Identify opportunities for continuous improvement of IT infrastructure and system administration, processes and practices taking into account international leading practices, improvement of business processes, cost reduction and productivity improvement. Manage all infrastructure implementations of software and hardware. • Administer and support all Cloud based business systems such as VoIP Telephone, Office 365 and SharePoint. Design, develop and implement information systems business solutions; Assess physical and technical security risks to data, software and hardware; Conduct reviews to assess quality assurance practices, software products and information systems. Budget and cost control. Analyze customer support metrics and refine processes. Coordinate with the asset management division to inventory, manage equipment assets portfolio management within the department. Design and implementation of basic and complex services related to IT. Design and planning of physical infrastructure projects. Design plans of preventive and corrective

maintenance of computer equipment. Manage Server data local & Cloud backups. Setup, management, operation & support operation of the business software system, the control system. Update IT documents and inventory. Training and advice administrative staff.

09/2018 – 09/2019 Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Cluster IT Manager Holiday Inn Bur Dubai - Embassy District & Holiday Inn Downtown -Deira

Strategically plan and operationally execute annual budget for the department as well as identify, plan and manage various IT hardware and software projects in all project stages to ensure project objectives are accomplished within time. Protect the confidentiality, integrity and availability of the company's data and IT infrastructure. Act as a resource person, solving computer problems for users. Manage and support all Network security, antivirus, Malware systems to ensure the company is protected from any threats. Develop and implement policies and procedures for electronic data processing and computer systems operations and development. Work closely with all departments to develop and support their computer system requirements. Implement cost saving and systems to improve overall staff use. Administer, implement and service all Internet, telecommunication and data communications infrastructure. Analyze all aspects of the IT hardware lifecycle and provide recommendations. Support initiatives regarding the business system, its use and integrity. Make recommendations regarding the life cycle of all hardware and software areas infrastructure. Completing an initial IT audit, with regular audits to follow on the state of the business as it pertains to IT. Analysis, planning and management of all aspects of the business' hardware and software systems. Design and implementation of the organization's technology strategy, including identifying needs, investigating trends and recommending solutions. Ensuring IT policies and procedures reflect best practices. Creating business efficiencies through IT. Monitoring security risks and implementing mitigation efforts. Clearly communicating IT processes and information to employees across business units and levels with regular IT updates to leadership. Disseminating IT policies and practices throughout the firm, ensuring adoption and compliance from all employees.

10/2016 – 09/2018 Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

Information Security & Technology Manager Intercontinental Abu Dhabi

Manage information technology and computer systems Plan, organize, control and evaluate IT and electronic data operations Manage IT staff by recruiting, training and coaching employees,

communicating job expectations and appraising their performance Design, develop, implement and coordinate systems, policies and procedures Ensure security of data, network access and backup systems Act in alignment with user needs and system functionality to contribute to organizational policy Identify problematic areas and implement strategic solutions in time Audit systems and assess their outcomes Preserve assets, information security and control structures Handle annual budget and ensure cost-effectiveness Project Management

04/2013 – 09/2016 Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

Asst Technology Manager InterContinental Hotels Group

Monitor the operation and security of all computer hardware and ensure that it is operating properly Maintain accurate inventory and record of all hardware, software and manuals purchased by the hotel Ensure that all software runs with no output errors, nonresponse time problems and functioning according to specifications Prepare a monthly report regarding the systems and issues related to the smooth operation of application software Maintain the documentation of the telephone system configuration and all MPT lines Understand all the department working procedures and perform the related tasks as described Carry out the repairs and maintenance of all PCs, printers, telephones, interactive system, key lock system, etc. Maintain all users access request and authorizations

(Windows, E-mail, Opera, Micros, Novell). Act as the primary contact for all outside agents in all computer technology-related matters Respond to all users request and provide them with adequate support Install and Configure Networks Assist & Support IT Director

08/2010 - 04/2013

IT Coordinator InterContinental Hotels & Resorts

Reporting to: IT Manager & Assistant General Manager Achievement: Promoted to IT Department In-Charge Good hands-on knowledge IN Micros Fidelio, Opera, and Saflok Key Encoder. Excellent experience in Windows 98, 2000, XP, Win 7, Server 2003, Server 2008etc. Monitoring, Maintenance, and Troubleshooting of Backups & Servers, IPTV & Locatel Server, Pagers, all Systems, Internet & Peripheral devices. Maintaining the Intercontinental Servers Handling Accounts software such as Sun & TMS Caller Counting. Installation, Configuration & Management of Domain & Exchange Server, wireless Networks, FBM software, Civilsoft Payroll HR Software etc. Management of BlackBerry Server, Exchange Server, Cyber Roam Firewall, ISA Server, Inn Gate Internet Access control software etc. Conducting Cross Training in IT for the staff.

05/2009 - 08/2010

IT Project Manager Trianon Hotels

Reporting to the General Manager & IT Director. Worked as Pre Opening team for 4 projects. Exclusively in-charge, of all the four Projects. Maintenance and Troubleshooting of IPTV. Maintaining the Trianon server, maintenance & troubleshooting of all systems, troubleshooting internet & peripheral devices. Handling Accounts software such as FBM, DPHS and TMS Caller Counting. Handling CCTV, PABX System. Good Knowledge in IDPMS Front Office Software. Good knowledge in POS Software. In Charge of Business Centre and Meeting Rooms. Complete In Charge of New Project.

02/2007 – 02/2009 Bangalore ,India

Hardware & Networking Faculty Jetking Infotrain Limited

Teach networking courses involving Microsoft and Cisco related platforms and operating systems, and other computer technology courses for which qualified to teach, to students. Implement or create labs and instruct students in the creation, performance and understanding of concepts related to course student learning outcomes in the following areas Network attacks and virus characteristics. Network Cabling Media (BaseT, Cat5, Fiber, etc.). Network Protocols, Ports and Services (i.e., TCP/IP, TFTP, DNS, DHCP, ICMP, FTP, HTTP, HTTPS, SMTP and VOIP). Utilize network addressing (MAC, 1Pv4,1Pv6). Configuration of File Servers, Proxy and Print Servers. Basic knowledge of Microsoft Office Applications (Word, Outlook, Excel). Remote Desktop and Remote Assistance. Network Security concepts (IDS, IPS, SSH, Encryption, Steganography). Logical, Physical and Wireless Topologies. Network Design and Devices (i.e., DMZ, IDF, MDF, Demarc, Hubs, Switches, Routers, Bridges, etc.). Help community college students further develop their technical knowledge and skills, and professional attitudes and behavior's, for college and workplace success. Facilitate student learning, provide effective instruction, and perform evaluations of student learning for all assigned classes, using each course's standard course outline as a guide. Be available to students via email, phone, or personal conferences. The method of contact and hours of availability should be clearly communicated to supervisors and to students through the course syllabus each semester. Meet all classes and other scheduled responsibilities such as office hours and meetings at the designated times. Receive training or stay current in technological or pedagogical advances that promote student learning, including learning and using Publisher's software when applicable.

Education

03/2016 - 01/2020 Information Systems | Master of Science in Information Systems Management

Systems Management University of Roehampton

02/2007 - 02/2008 Hardware & Networking | Diploma in Hardware &

Bengaluru, India Networking

JETKING Hardware & Networking Institute

CCNA, CWNA, N+, OS Specialization etc.

02/2004 – 02/2007 Pharmacy | Diploma in Pharmacy M.S. Ramaiah College of Pharmacy

* Skills

Team Management Decision Making Targeting & Achieving Goals Strategic thinking
Negotiating Controlling Financials Adapting Time Management Team Building
Teamwork Collaboration Leadership Active Listening
Communicating Complex Information in Digestible Amounts IP Setup Wireless Modems/Routers
Cloud Services Cyber Security Information Management Cloud Systems Administration
Goal-Oriented Digital Communications Manage Remote Working Teams
Continually Review Processes for Improvement Multitasking Meeting Deadlines
ICT(Information and Communications Technology)
Analyze and Recommend Database Improvements
Analyze Impact of Database Changes to the Business Audit Database Access and Requests
Application and Server Monitoring Tools Azure Configuration Management Critical Thinking
Database Administration Develop and Secure Network Structures Emerging Technologies
File Systems Implement Backup and Recovery Plan Information Systems
Install, Maintain, and Merge Databases Integrated Technologies Internet Optimization
IT Soft Skills Logical Thinking Operating Systems Problem Solving Project Management
Networking Initiative; Effective interpersonal skills Team player
Excellent oral & written communication

Languages

Acquisition & Deployment











T Certificates

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS) 03/2009

Microsoft

Certification Number: B964-3660

01/2009 **Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer: Security (MCSE)**

Microsoft

Certification Number: B964-3653

Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator 01/2009

Certification Number: B964-3652

01/2009 Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator: Messaging

(MCSA) Microsoft

Certification Number: B964-3655

01/2009 **Microsoft Certified IT Professional (MCP)**

Microsoft

Certification Number: B964-3645

Y Awards

2017 Shortlist: IT Person of the Year

Hotelier Awards

https://www.hoteliermiddleeast.com/31886-hotelierawards-2017-shortlistit-

person-of-the-year/

Top 5 among 300 candidates.

Manager of the Year 2014

InterContinental Hotel

References

Upon Request

Hobbies



Exploring distant



Getting lost in a good books



Capturing moments



Feeling the music



Every kind of sports



Dog Training



Playing Billiards



Playing Indoor